<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<content>
<type>anchor_paper</type>
<title>Opinion</title>
<rubric>rubric_page522</rubric>
<papers>

  <paper level="1">
    <text><![CDATA[	{i}{o}{v}Wild {c}wheI{/c} cars look like some cars. {c}they{/c} come in a lot of colers. {sf}They are strong and do not {wc}brake{/wc} and I want to colect them al.{/sf} my brothur has this one car. It is blu and. It has a red hud. I steped on my cars lots of times. It is hard to get the cars. {sf}There are lots.{/sf} I want to get som as presints. My brothur and me like to rase {wc}are{/wc} cars. His has a yello strippe on the dor. It is very cool.  {/i}{/o}{/v}
]]></text>
  </paper>
  
  <paper level="2">
    <text><![CDATA[	{sf}{v}{i}I have a lot of {c}wild whels cars.{/c}{/i}{o} {i}They look like {wc}some cars.{/wc} {c}they{/c} come in a lot of colers, to. They are strong. They do not brak I want to colect them all.{/sf} My brothur has this one car. it is a blu one. It has a red hud. I have steped on my cars lots of times. It hard to {wc}get{/wc} the cars. There are so many. I saw one with a yello strippe on the door. I realy like wild wheels cars.{/o}{/v}
]]></text>
  </paper>
  
  <paper level="3">
    <text><![CDATA[	{v}Wild Wheels Cars are great toys. {i}{o}{o}One reason{/o} I like them is because they {c}lok{/c} like {wc}some cars.{/wc} {sf}They come in a lot of colers, to. They are {wc}kind of strong{/wc}. They do not break. I have steped on my cars many times. {c}i{/c} got many Wild Wheels Cars as presents. I am trying to colect them all.{/sf} It is very hard to do because there are so many. my brother has a purple car. It has a yellow strippe on the door. It is his favorite.{/i}{/o}{/v} 
 ]]></text>
  </paper>

  <paper level="4">
    <text><![CDATA[	{sf}{v}{o}{i}Wild Wheels Cars are the best toys.{/i}{/o} {o}One reason{/o} I like them is {c}becuse{/c} they look like cars. {c}they{/c} come in {wc}a lot of shapes and colors.{/wc} they have strippes painted on the doors. {o}Another reason{/o} I like them is because the cars are {wc}strong.{/wc} You can drop them. You can step on them.{/sf} {wc}My grandma gave me a red Wild Wheels Car. It has yellow stripes on it. It also has blue doors and a purple hood.{/wc} I like it very much. {o}I think every kid should have one.{/o}{/v}  
]]></text>
  </paper>
  
  <paper level="5">
    <text><![CDATA[	{sf}{v}{o}{i}Wild Wheels Cars are the best toys for kids.{/i}{/o} {i}{o}One reason{/o} I like them is because they {wc}look like race cars.{/wc} {c}they{/c} come in {wc}different shapes and colors.{/wc} They also have {c}strippes{/c} painted on the doors. {o}Another reason{/o} I like them is because the cars are {wc}tough.{/wc} You can step on them and drop them on the ground.{/sf} Some Wild Wheels Cars come with a remote control. {sf}You can drive your car around a parking lot and make it do {wc}fun tricks.{/i}{/wc}{/sf}{o} I think every kid should buy a Wild Wheels Car.{/o}{/v} 
]]></text>
  </paper>  
  
  <paper level="6">
    <text><![CDATA[	{sf}{v}{o}{i}Wild Wheels Cars are the best toys for kids.{/i}{/o} {i}{o}{o}One reason{/o} I like them is they {wc}look just like real race cars.{/wc} They come in {wc}different sizes, shapes, and colors.{/wc} They also have racing stripes painted on the doors. {o}Another reason{/o} I like them is the cars are {wc}sturdy{/wc}. They do not break if you step on them or drop them on the ground.{/sf} {o}Best of all,{/o} some Wild Wheels Cars come with a remote control. You can drive your car around a parking lot and make it do {wc}cool tricks.{/i}{/o}{/wc} I think every kid should buy a Wild Wheels Car.{/v} 
]]></text>
  </paper>    
  
  
  </papers>
</content>
